### Emanuele Viglianisi

Software Engineer (Data) emavgl@gmail.com https://emavgl.github.io

My name is Emanuele and I am originally from the beautiful island of Sicily in Italy. After completing my Bachelor's degree in Catania, I pursued a Master's degree in Computer Science with a focus on Data and Security at University of Trento. Following my studies, I worked as a Researcher at Fondazione Bruno Kessler for two years before moving to Linz, Austria to join the Data Team at Runtastic as a Software Engineer. In my free time, I enjoy running, cooking (and eating), reading, and exploring new places.

### Experiences

#### • [2020-2023] Software Engineer (Data) at Runtastic

At Runtastic, I worked as Software Engineer in the Data Team. My main focus was on data architecture design, managing data exchange with adidas, and improving our data platform and CI/CD.

- I contributed to the migration of data and data platform to a cloud based solution, based on Databricks and Microsoft Azure.
- I took part in designing and implementing the architecture of our data platform, including the ETL pipelines, systems to ensure GDPR compilance and data quality, CI/CD tooling, ad alerting.
- I have implemented data products connected to backend services such as follower recommendations and retention models.
- In Q1 2022, I worked in the Android Team developing new features for the adidas Running and adidas Training android apps.
- In Q3 2022, I worked with the adidas sales Data & Analytics team advising on best practices and collaborating with the team to implement the first ETL streaming pipeline serving an almost real-time dashboard used for making quick decisions during key selling moments (e.g., Black Friday).
- Technologies: Python, PySpark, Databricks, Microsoft Azure, Kotlin

#### • [2018-2019] Software Engineer and Researcher at Fondazione Bruno Kessler (FBK)

- I worked on a European funded project (EIT Digital) in the fintech domain. I developed a new state-of-the-art blackbox testing tool to run functional and security tests on RESTful APIs. The associated research paper won the Distinguished Paper Award at the ICST 2020 conference. Previously, I worked on a block-box security testing tool for Ethereum Smart Contract.
- In Q4 2019 I was Teaching assistant for the master course titled "Security Testing" at the University of Trento. Topics: OWASP top 10 vulnerabilities and how to write automatic test-cases using Selenium to attack and assert the fix of the vulnerable applications.
- Technologies: Python, Z3, Blockchain (Ethereum), Solidity, Web3JS, Truffle Framework, Node.JS, Java, Gradle.

#### **Educations**

- [2016 2018] Master of Science Computer Science, Università di Trento
- [2013 2016] Bachelor's degree Computer Science, University of Catania

# Certifications

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate

# Webinar and Conferences

- Big Data Week 2022 Bucharest and Big Data Conference Europe 2022
  ZERO2HERO: An Advanced Data Platform To Drive User Engagement, Emanuele Viglianisi, Daniele Montesi
- Data+AI Summit Europe, 2020-11-18 and CI/CD Template Webinar, 2020-10-20
  Developing ML-enabled Data Pipelines on Databricks using IDE & CI/CD at Runtastic, Emanuele Viglianisi, Michael Shtelma

#### **Publications**

Check my profile on Google Scholar.

- RESTTESTGEN: Automated Black-Box Testing of RESTful APIs (Distinguished Paper Award)
  E Viglianisi, M Dallago, M Ceccato 2020 IEEE 13th International Conference on Software Testing,
  Validation and Verification (ICST)
- A federated society of bots for smart contract testing E Viglianisi, M Ceccato, P Tonella Journal of Systems and Software, 110647